Schwyn Francis



schwynf@gmail.com



6309039996



linkedin.com/in/schwyn-francis-5a47a9199



https://schwyn-francis.herokuapp.com/

Summary

Experienced professional with a demonstrated history of client facing work and completing team projects. I work for Maricopa County Environmental Services in the Aquatic Health & Safety Department. I'm a Junior Web Developer with a Bachelors of Science (B.S) in Biological Sciences. 2+ years of JavaScript experience. I recently earned a Full Stack Web Development certificate from the University of Arizona. Main focus is MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack for server side development.

Experience



Environmental Health Specialist

Maricopa County Environmental Services

Sep 2016 - Present (4 years 1 month +)

EHS inspector for the Aquatics Health & Safety Department.

Regulate Maricopa County Environmental Health Code.

Conduct public & semi-public swimming pool construction inspections and manage over 700 permits for routine compliance.

Train new employees.

Laboratory Technician III

Doctor's Data, Inc.

Mar 2014 - Jun 2016 (2 years 4 months)

Conducted chemical analyses on body fluids, such as blood or urine, using LC/MS systems.

Worked with Agilent MassHunter Workstation, Orchard Harvest and Labvantage for instrument control, data acquisition, qualitative and quantitative data analysis, and reporting.

Provided support to the research and development staff in the Chromatography Department.

Team Lead.

Education



Illinois State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Biology/Biological Sciences, General 2011 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications



Certified Pool Operator Certificate

Registered Environmental Health Specialist/Registered Sanitarian (REHSRS) - Arizona

Department of Health Services

Issued Jan 2020 - Expires Dec 2020

Full Stack Web Development - University of Arizona

Skills

JavaScript • jQuery • MySQL • MongoDB • indexedDB • Node.js • React.js • Express.js • GitHub • Heroku

Honors & Awards

New Employee Of The Year - Maricopa County Environmental Services

Aug 2017 performance-driven